wnyc.org 2016-06-28

# Privacy Policy

_Last updated on July 2, 2014. Please also see ourTerms of Service. _

### New York Public Radio’s Digital Platforms

This Privacy Policy, along with our Terms of Service, applies to all users of New York Public Radio’s (NYPR’s) digital platforms, including, e.g., this website (and all of NYPR’s other websites, like wnyc.org and wqxr.org, that link to this Privacy Policy), embeddable content that we may make available for use on other people’s websites or digital platforms, and our apps, other than third party content, discussed in Other Sites and Services, below.

We take your privacy seriously and want you to understand how we do and don’t use information about you.

### How We Collect Information

**Information We Collect Automatically From Users**

When you use our digital platforms, we may automatically recognize information like your IP address, operating system, what type of device you’re using, geotargeting information (what geographic area you’re in), and your user behavior (e.g. how long you stay on the website).

NYPR uses cookies, other similar small files sent to your computer which store information through your browser and web beacons (tiny graphics, aka “pixel tags”) as part of our digital functionality (e.g. to store your preferences or password and understand your user behavior), and to offer responsive elements based on users’ actions.

In addition, NYPR uses third party vendors that provide services for our digital platforms (e.g. analytics) which may each use their own cookies and web beacons as part of our digital platforms.

**Information Users Give Us Voluntarily**

You may voluntarily give us information like:

  * Your login information
  * Your email address (e.g. when you sign up for a newsletter)
  * Your responses to surveys or contests (each contest will also have its own rules that apply)
  * Your content submissions (e.g. in response to a call for snowstorm photos)
  * Your comments on articles
  * Your phone number (e.g. if you text us)
  * Pledge/donation information
  * Purchase information for our ticketed events

### How We Use Information

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We do not store users’ passwords. When we ask for personally identifiable information (like your name, address, email address, phone number or credit card information), we only use the information you give us within the NYPR family of services, except as noted below under “List Sharing,” and as described below when you submit as part of a public feature. This means, e.g., we may email you to invite you to join a new newsletter list, invite you to Greene Space events, or ask you to renew your membership when it expires, and we may share your information with third party vendors, but only for the purpose of helping us do these sorts of things (and not for their own use).

If you do not wish to be contacted based on this information, please indicate your preference by opting out on the pledge form or through the opt-out information provided in the email you receive, or contact [Listener Services](http://www.wnyc.org/contact/). We will do our best to make your change in a timely manner. You should also contact Listener Services if you would like to review or correct your information.

We may also aggregate your personally identifiable information (such as your address) with others to produce non-personally identifiable information that we may use to analyze and improve what we do.

**Payment Information**

When you provide us payment information in order to process a pledge or purchase a ticket, this information is encrypted, using reasonable, industry-standard security measures, and is used (generally by our third party vendors) only to fulfill your pledge.

**Non Personally Identifiable Information**

We use other information (other than personal information and payment information) for things like improving your user experience (e.g. your user history on our digital platforms may be used to provide recommendations to you and other users of the same device), selecting third-party vendors who best meet our needs, notifying our users about our programs and events, and helping foundation and corporate funders better understand our audience. In doing this, we do share non-personally identifying information and payment information with third parties.

Please note that if you share personal information through a public feature that it may become public (e.g. if you include your email address in a comment, other users will see it, or if you include your name in a content submission, it may be read on the air or posted online to attribute the content).

Lastly, if we are required by law to share your information (including personal and payment information), we will share to the extent necessary to comply with the request.

### List Sharing Policy

We may occasionally share users’ names and postal addresses (but not email addresses) with carefully selected organizations. If you do not want your address exchanged in this way, please contact [Listener Services](http://www.wnyc.org/contact/) to ask that your name and address be removed from any shared mailing lists.

It is NYPR policy not to sell or exchange email addresses or phone numbers with any organization. If any situation comes up in which we would like to share this information with someone else (e.g. if we collect your email while ticketing an event, and want to share with our co-presenter), we will ask for your permission.

### Other Sites and Services

Our digital platforms contain links to services maintained by third parties that do not follow the same privacy practices as NYPR. In some cases, we may also include certain embedded tools provided and controlled by third parties, or that permit you to submit information to third parties. These services and tools are governed by the terms and policies of those third parties. Our digital platforms also include widgets from third party services, e.g. a button that allows you to “like” an article on Facebook. All of these third party services have their own terms and policies. Please review these services’ own privacy policies for more information. Details on certain third party services used by NYPR and opt outs will be maintained and updated here. 

### Contests

From time to time, we may offer contests that users may enter through our digital platforms. Please note that these contests may each have their own official rules, which give NYPR additional rights to use entries, and which govern your participation in the contest. 

### Changes to Privacy Policy

NYPR will notify users who have registered login information and an email address of changes to this Privacy Policy (other than changes to the third party services list, which may be updated from time to time), and any changes will only take effect prospectively from the date of the change. If you have additional questions about how your personal information may be used or if you have questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](http://www.wnyc.org/contact/).
